<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">

<class>
	<classname>Barbarian</classname>
	<proficiency>Strength, Constitution</proficiency>
	<description>Barbarians, different as they might be, are defined by their rage: unbridled, unquenchable, and
	unthinking fury. More than a mere emotion, their anger is the ferocity of a cornered predator, the unrelenting assault
	of a storm, the churning turmoil of the sea. For some, their rage springs from a communion with fierce animal spirits.
	Others draw from a roiling reservoir of anger at a world full of pain. For every barbarian, rage is a power that fuels
	not just a battle frenzy but also uncanny reflexes, resilience, and feats of strength.</description>
</class>

<class>
	<classname>Bard</classname>
	<proficiency>Dexterity, Charisma</proficiency>
	<description>Whether scholar, skald, or scoundrel, a bard weaves magic through words and music to inspire allies,
	demoralize foes, manipulate minds, create illusions, and even heal wounds.</description>
</class>

<class>
	<classname>Cleric</classname>
	<proficiency>Wisdom, Charisma</proficiency>
	<description>Clerics are intermediaries between the mortal world and the distant planes of the gods. As varied as the
	gods they serve, clerics strive to embody the handiwork of their deities. No ordinary priest, a cleric is imbued with
	divine magic.</description>
</class>

<class>
	<classname>Druid</classname>
	<proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom</proficiency>
	<description>Whether calling on the elemental forces of nature or emulating the creatures of the animal world, druids
	are an embodiment of nature&#39;s resilience, cunning, and fury. They claim no mastery over nature. Instead, they see
	themselves as extensions of nature&#39;s indomitable will.</description>
</class>

<class>
	<classname>Fighter</classname>
	<proficiency>Strength, Constitution</proficiency>
	<description>Questing knights, conquering overlords, royal champions, elite foot soldiers, hardened mercenaries, and
	bandit kings&#8211;as fighters, they all share an unparalleled mastery with weapons and armor, and a thorough knowledge of
	the skills of combat. And they are well acquainted with death, both meting it out and staring it defiantly in the
	face.</description>
</class>

<class>
	<classname>Monk</classname>
	<proficiency>Strength, Dexterity</proficiency>
	<description>Whatever their discipline, monks are united in their ability to magically harness the energy
	that flows in their bodies. Whether channeled as a striking display of combat prowess or a subtler focus of
	defensive ability and speed, this energy infuses all that a monk does.</description>
</class>

<class>
	<classname>Paladin</classname>
	<proficiency>Wisdom, Charisma</proficiency>
	<description>Whatever their origin and their mission, paladins are united by their oaths to stand against the forces of
	evil. Whether sworn before a god&#39;s altar and the witness of a priest, in a sacred glade before nature spirits and fey
	beings, or in a moment of desperation and grief with the dead as the only witness, a paladin&#39;s oath is a powerful
	bond. It is a source of power that turns a devout warrior into a blessed champion.</description>
</class>

<class>
	<classname>Ranger</classname>
	<proficiency>Strength, Dexterity</proficiency>
	<description>Warriors of the wilderness, rangers specialize in hunting the monsters that threaten the edges of
	civilization—humanoid raiders, rampaging beasts and monstrosities, terrible giants, and deadly dragons. Though a ranger
	might make a living as a hunter, a guide, or a tracker, a ranger&#39;s true calling is to defend the outskirts of
	civilization from the ravages of monsters and humanoid hordes that press in from the wild.</description>
</class>

<class>
	<classname>Rogue</classname>
	<proficiency>Dexterity, Intelligence</proficiency>
	<description>Rogues rely on skill, stealth, and their foes&#39; vulnerabilities to get the upper hand in any situation.
	They have a knack for finding the solution to just about any problem, demonstrating a resourcefulness and versatility
	that is the cornerstone of any successful adventuring party.</description>
</class>

<class>
	<classname>Sorcerer</classname>
	<proficiency>Constitution, Charisma</proficiency>
	<description>Sorcerers carry a magical birthright conferred upon them by an exotic bloodline, some otherworldly
	influence, or exposure to unknown cosmic forces. One can&#39;t study sorcery as one learns a language, any more than one
	can learn to live a legendary life. No one chooses sorcery; the power chooses the sorcerer.</description>
</class>

<class>
	<classname>Warlock</classname>
	<proficiency>Wisdom, Charisma</proficiency>
	<description>Warlocks are seekers of the knowledge that lies hidden in the fabric of the multiverse. Through pacts
	made with mysterious beings of supernatural power, warlocks unlock magical effects both subtle and spectacular. Drawing
	on the ancient knowledge of beings such as fey nobles, demons, devils, hags, and alien entities of the Far Realm,
	warlocks piece together arcane secrets to bolster their own power.</description>
</class>

<class>
	<classname>Wizard</classname>
	<proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom</proficiency>
	<description>Wizards are supreme magic&#8211;users, defined and united as a class by the spells they cast. Drawing on the
	subtle weave of magic that permeates the cosmos, wizards cast spells of explosive fire, arcing lightning, subtle
	deception, and brute&#8211;force mind control. Their magic conjures monsters from other planes of existence, glimpses the
	future, or turns slain foes into zombies. Their mightiest spells change one substance into another, call meteors
	down from the sky, or open portals to other worlds.</description>
</class>
</compendium>
