<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<a></a>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
<race>
	<racename>Dragonborn</racename>
	<racedescription>Born of dragons, as their name proclaims, the dragonborn walk proudly through a world that greets
	them with fearful incomprehension. Shaped by draconic gods or the dragons themselves, dragonborn originally
	hatched from dragon eggs as a unique race, combining the best attributes of dragons and humanoids. Some dragonborn
	are faithful servants to true dragons, others form the ranks of soldiers in great wars, and still others find
	themselves adrift, with no clear calling in life.</racedescription>
</race>

<race>
	<racename>Dwarf</racename>
	<racedescription>Bold and hardy, dwarves are known as skilled warriors, miners, and workers of stone and metal.
	Though they stand well under 5 feet tall, dwarves are so broad and compact that they can weigh as much as a human
	standing nearly two feet taller. Their courage and endurance are also easily a match for any of the larger folk.</racedescription>
</race>

<race>
	<racename>Elf</racename>
	<racedescription>Elves are a magical people of otherworldly grace, living in the world but not entirely part of it.
	They live in places of ethereal beauty, in the midst of ancient forests or in silvery spires glittering with faerie
	light, where soft music drifts through the air and gentle fragrances waft on the breeze. Elves love nature and magic,
	art and artistry, music and poetry, and the good things of the world.</racedescription>
</race>

<race>
	<racename>Gnome</racename>
	<racedescription>A constant hum of busy activity pervades the warrens and neighborhoods where gnomes form their
	closeknit communities. Louder sounds punctuate the hum: a crunch of grinding gears here, a minor explosion there, a
	yelp of surprise or triumph, and especially bursts of laughter. Gnomes take delight in life, enjoying every moment of
	invention, exploration, investigation, creation, and play.</racedescription>
</race>

<race>
	<racename>Halfling</racename>
	<racedescription>The comforts of home are the goals of most halflings' lives : a place to se ttle in peace and quiet,
	far from marauding monsters and clashing armies; a blazing fire and a generous meal; fine drink and fine conversation.
	Though some halflings live out their days in remote agricultural communities, others form nomadic bands that travel
	constantly, lured by the open road and the wide horizon to discover the wonders of new lands and peoples. But even these wanderers love peace,
	food, hearth, and home, though home might be a wagon jostling along an dirt road or a raft floating downriver.</racedescription>
</race>

<race>
	<racename>Half-Elf</racename>
	<racedescription>Walking in two worlds but truly belonging to neither, half-elves combine what some say are the best qualities of their elf and
	human parents: human curiosity, inventiveness, and ambition tempered by the refined senses, love of nature, and artistic tastes of the elves.
	Some half-elves live among humans, set apart by their emotional and physical differences, watching friends and loved ones age while time barely touches
	them. Others live with the elves, growing restless as they reach adulthood in the timeless elven realms, while their peers continue to
	live as children. Many half-elves, unable to fit into either society, choose lives of solitary wandering or join with other misfits and outcasts in the adventuring life.</racedescription>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<speed>30</speed>
	<ability>Cha 2</ability>
	<proficiency></proficiency>
	<trait>
		<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
		<text>Two different ability scores of your choice increase by 1.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Darkvision</name>
		<text>Thanks to your elf blood, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
		<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Skill Versatility</name>
		<text>You gain proficiency in two skills of your choice.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<languages>You can speak, read, and write Common, Elvish, and one extra language of your choice.</languages>
	</trait>
</race>

<race>
	<racename>Half-Orc</racename>
	<racedescription>Whether united under the leadership of a mighty warlock or having fought to a standstill after years of conflict, orc and
	human tribes sometimes form alliances, joining forces into a larger horde to the terror of civilized lands nearby. When these alliances are sealed
	by marriages, half-orcs are born. Some half-orcs rise to become proud chiefs of orc tribes, their human blood giving them an edge over their full-blooded
	orc rivals. Some venture into the world to prove their worth among humans and other more civilized races. Many of these become
	adventurers, achieving greatness for their mighty deeds and notoriety for their barbaric customs and savage fury.</racedescription>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<speed>30</speed>
	<ability>Str 2, Con 1</ability>
	<proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
	<trait>
		<name>Darkvision</name>
		<text>Thanks to your orc blood, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Menacing</name>
		<text>You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Relentless Endurance</name>
		<text>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Savage Attacks</name>
		<text>When you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack, you can roll one of the weapon's damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of the critical hit.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<languages>You can speak, read, and write Common and Orc. Orc is a harsh, grating language with hard consonants.</languages>
	</trait>
</race>

<race>
	<racename>Human</racename>
	<racedescription>In the reckonings of most worlds, humans are the youngest of the common races, late to arrive on the world scene and short-lived
	in comparison to dwarves, elves, and dragons. Perhaps it is because of their shorter lives that they strive to achieve as much as they can in the years
	they are given. Or maybe they feel they have something to prove to the elder races, and that’s why they build their mighty empires on the foundation of conquest
	and trade. Whatever drives them, humans are the innovators, the achievers, and the pioneers of the worlds.</racedescription>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<speed>30</speed>
	<ability>Str 1, Dex 1, Con 1, Int 1, Wis 1, Cha 1</ability>
	<proficiency></proficiency>
	<trait>
		<languages>You can speak, read, and write Common and one extra language of your choice.</languages>
	</trait>
</race>

<race>
	<racename>Tiefling</racename>
	<racedescription>To be greeted with stares and whispers, to suffer violence and insult on the street, to see mistrust and fear in every eye: this is the lot of the
	tiefling. And to twist the knife, tieflings know that this is because a pact struck generations ago infused the essence of Asmodeus—overlord of the Nine Hells—into their
	bloodline. Their appearance and their nature are not their fault but the result of an ancient sin, for which they and their children
	and their children’s children will always be held accountable.</racedescription>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<speed>30</speed>
	<ability>Cha 2, Int 1</ability>
	<proficiency></proficiency>
	<trait>
		<name>Darkvision</name>
		<text>Thanks to your infernal heritage, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Hellish Resistance</name>
		<text>You have resistance to fire damage.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Infernal Legacy</name>
		<text>You know the thaumaturgy cantrip. Once you reach 3rd level, you can cast the hellish rebuke spell once per day as a 2nd-level spell. Once you reach 5th level, you can also cast the darkness spell once per day. You must finish a long rest to cast either of these spells again using this trait. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<languages>You can speak, read, and write Common and Infernal.</languages>
	</trait>
</race>
</compendium>
