<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
<race>
	<Dragonborn>
		<subrace>
			<Dragonbornname>Black</Dragonbornname>
			<Dragonborndescr>While Dragonborn do not have a subrace, they do have a draconic ancestry, which denotes the color
			of the dragon, its damage type, and its breath weapon. Damage Type: Acid. Breath Weapon: 5 by 30 ft line (Dex save).</Dragonborndescr>
		</subrace>
		<subrace>
			<Dragonbornname>Blue</Dragonbornname>
			<Dragonborndescr>While Dragonborn do not have a subrace, they do have a draconic ancestry, which denotes the color
			of the dragon, its damage type, and its breath weapon. Damage Type: Lightning. Breath Weapon: 5 by 30 ft line (Dex save).</Dragonborndescr>
		</subrace>
		<subrace>
			<Dragonbornname>Brass</Dragonbornname>
			<Dragonborndescr>While Dragonborn do not have a subrace, they do have a draconic ancestry, which denotes the color
			of the dragon, its damage type, and its breath weapon. Damage Type: Fire. Breath Weapon: 5 by 30 ft line (Dex save).</Dragonborndescr>
		</subrace>
		<subrace>
			<Dragonbornname>Bronze</Dragonbornname>
			<Dragonborndescr>While Dragonborn do not have a subrace, they do have a draconic ancestry, which denotes the color
			of the dragon, its damage type, and its breath weapon. Damage Type: Lightning. Breath Weapon: 5 by 30 ft line (Dex save).</Dragonborndescr>
		</subrace>
		<subrace>
			<Dragonbornname>Copper</Dragonbornname>
			<Dragonborndescr>While Dragonborn do not have a subrace, they do have a draconic ancestry, which denotes the color
			of the dragon, its damage type, and its breath weapon. Damage Type: Acid. Breath Weapon: 5 by 30 ft line (Dex save).</Dragonborndescr>
		</subrace>
		<subrace>
			<Dragonbornname>Gold</Dragonbornname>
			<Dragonborndescr>While Dragonborn do not have a subrace, they do have a draconic ancestry, which denotes the color
			of the dragon, its damage type, and its breath weapon. Damage Type: Fire. Breath Weapon: 15 ft cone (Dex save).</Dragonborndescr>
		</subrace>
		<subrace>
			<Dragonbornname>Green</Dragonbornname>
			<Dragonborndescr>While Dragonborn do not have a subrace, they do have a draconic ancestry, which denotes the color
			of the dragon, its damage type, and its breath weapon. Damage Type: Poison. Breath Weapon: 15 ft cone (Con save).</Dragonborndescr>
		</subrace>
		<subrace>
			<Dragonbornname>Red</Dragonbornname>
			<Dragonborndescr>While Dragonborn do not have a subrace, they do have a draconic ancestry, which denotes the color
			of the dragon, its damage type, and its breath weapon. Damage Type: Fire. Breath Weapon: 15 ft cone (Dex save).</Dragonborndescr>
		</subrace>
		<subrace>
			<Dragonbornname>Silver</Dragonbornname>
			<Dragonborndescr>While Dragonborn do not have a subrace, they do have a draconic ancestry, which denotes the color
			of the dragon, its damage type, and its breath weapon. Damage Type: Cold. Breath Weapon: 15 ft cone (Con save).</Dragonborndescr>
		</subrace>
		<subrace>
			<Dragonbornname>White</Dragonbornname>
			<Dragonborndescr>While Dragonborn do not have a subrace, they do have a draconic ancestry, which denotes the color
			of the dragon, its damage type, and its breath weapon. Damage Type: Cold. Breath Weapon: 15 ft cone (Con save).</Dragonborndescr>
		</subrace>
	</Dragonborn>
</race>

<race>
	<Dwarf>
		<subrace>
			<Dwarfname>Hill Dwarf</Dwarfname>
			<Dwarfdescr>As a hill dwarf, you have keen senses, deep intuition, and remarkable resilience.</Dwarfdescr>
		</subrace>
		<subrace>
			<Dwarfname>Mountain Dwarf</Dwarfname>
			<Dwarfdescr>As a mountain dwarf, you're strong and hardy, accustomed to a difficult life in rugged terrain. You’re
			probably on the tall side (for a dwarf), and tend toward lighter coloration.</Dwarfdescr>
		</subrace>
	</Dwarf>
</race>

<race>
	<Elf>
		<subrace>
			<Elfname>High Elf</Elfname>
			<Elfdescr>As a high elf, you have a keen mind and a mastery of at least the basics of magic. In many of the worlds
			of D and D, there are two kinds of high elves. One type is haughty and reclusive, believing themselves to be superior to
			non-elves and even other elves. The other type are more common and more friendly, and often encountered among humans
			and other races.</Elfdescr>
		</subrace>
			<subrace>
			<Elfname>Wood Elf</Elfname>
			<Elfdescr>As a wood elf, you have keen senses and intuition, and your fleet feet carry you quickly and stealthily
			through your native forests.</Elfdescr>
		</subrace>
			<subrace>
			<Elfname>Dark Elf (Drow)</Elfname>
			<Elfdescr>Descended from an earlier subrace of dark-skinned elves, the drow were banished from the surface world
			for following the goddess Lolth down the path to evil and corruption. Now they have built their own
			civilization in the depths of the Underdark, patterned after the Way of Lolth.</Elfdescr>
		</subrace>
	</Elf>
</race>

<race>
	<Gnome>
		<subrace>
			<Gnomename>Forest Gnome</Gnomename>
			<Gnomedescr>As a forest gnome, you have a natural knack for illusion and inherent quickness and stealth. They
			gather in hidden communities in sylvan forests, using illusions and trickery to conceal themselves from
			threats or to mask their escape should they be detected. Forest gnomes tend to be friendly with other
			good-spirited woodland folk, and they regard elves and good fey as their most important allies. These gnomes
			also befriend small forest animals and rely on them for information about threats that might prowl their lands.</Gnomedescr>
		</subrace>
		<subrace>
			<Gnomename>Rock Gnome</Gnomename>
			<Gnomedescr>As a rock gnome, you have a natural inventiveness and hardiness beyond that of other gnomes.</Gnomedescr>
		</subrace>
	</Gnome>
</race>

<race>
	<Halfling>
		<subrace>
			<Halflingname>Lightfoot</Halflingname>
			<Halflingdescr>As a lightfoot halfling, you can easily hide from notice, even using other people as cover. You’re
			inclined to be affable and get along well with others. Lightfoots are more prone to wanderlust than other
			halflings, and often dwell alongside other races or take up a nomadic life.</Halflingdescr>
		</subrace>
		<subrace>
			<Halflingname>Stout</Halflingname>
			<Halflingdescr>As a stout halfling, you’re hardier than average and have some resistance to poison. Some say that
			stouts have dwarven blood.</Halflingdescr>
		</subrace>
	</Halfling>
</race>

<race>
	<Half-Elf>
		<!-- No subraces for this race -->
	</Half-Elf>
</race>

<race>
	<Half-Orc>
		<!-- No subraces for this race -->
	</Half-Orc>
</race>

<race>
	<Human>
		<!-- No subraces for this race -->
	</Human>
</race>

<race>
	<Tiefling>
		<!-- No subraces for this race -->
	</Tiefling>
</race>
</compendium>
