<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
<class>	<name>Cleric</name>	<hd>8</hd>	<proficiency>Wisdom, Charisma</proficiency>	<spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>		<autolevel level="1">			<feature>				<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>				<text>Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields</text>				<text>Weapons: simple weapons</text>				<text>Tools: none</text>				<text>Skills: Choose two from History, Insight, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion</text>			</feature>			<feature>				<name>Starting Equipment</name>				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>				<text> </text>				<text>&#8226; (a) a mace or (b) a warhammer (if proficient)</text>				<text>&#8226; (a) scale mail, (b) leather armor, or (c) chain mail (if proficient)</text>				<text>&#8226; (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</text>				<text>&#8226; (a) a priest's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>				<text>&#8226; A shield and a holy symbol</text>				<text> </text>				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 x 10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>			</feature>		</autolevel>	<autolevel level="1">		<slots>3, 2</slots>		<feature>			<name>Spellcasting</name>			<text>As a conduit for divine power, you can cast cleric spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the cleric spell list.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Cantrips:</text>			<text>	At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the cleric spell list. You learn an additional cleric cantrip of your choice at 4th level and another at 10th level. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Preparing and Casting Spells:</text>			<text>	The Cleric table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>			<text>	You prepare the list of cleric spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the cleric spell list. When you do so, choose a number of cleric spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your cleric level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>			<text>	For example, if you are a 3rd-level cleric, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells.</text>			<text>	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of cleric spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>			<text>	Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your cleric spells. The power of your spells comes from your devotion to your deity. You use your Wisdom whenever a cleric spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a cleric spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>			<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>			<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Ritual Casting:</text>			<text>	You can cast a cleric spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Spellcasting Focus:</text>			<text>	You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your cleric spells.</text>		</feature>		<feature>			<name>Divine Domain</name>			<text>Choose one domain related to your deity: Knowledge, Life, Light, Nature, Tempest, Trickery, or War. Each domain is detailed at the end of the class description, and each one provides examples of gods associated with it. Your choice grants you domain spells and other features when you choose it at 1st level. It also grants you additional ways to use Channel Divinity when you gain that feature at 2nd level, and additional benefits at 6th, 8th, and 17th levels. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Domain Spells:</text>			<text>	Each domain has a list of spells &#8212; its domain spells &#8212;  that you gain at the cleric levels noted in the domain description. Once you gain a domain spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</text>			<text>	If you have a domain spell that doesn't appear on the cleric spell list, the spell is nonetheless a cleric spell for you.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Death Domain</name>			<text>The Death domain is concerned with the forces that cause death, as well as the negative energy that gives rise to undead creatures. Deities such as Chemosh, Myrkul, and WeeJas are patrons of necromancers, death knights, liches, mummy lords, and vampires. Gods of the Death domain also embody murder (Anubis, Bhaal, and Pyremius), pain (Iuz or Loviatar), disease or poison (Incabulos, Talona, or Morgion), and the underworld (Hades and He!). </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Death Domain Spells:</text>			<text>	At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared</text>			<text>	1st &#8212; false life, ray of sickness</text>			<text>	3rd &#8212; blindness/deafness, ray of enfeeblement</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; animate dead, vampiric touch</text>			<text>	7th &#8212; blight, death ward</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; antilife shell, cloudkill</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Bonus Proficiency (Death Domain)</name>			<text>When the cleric chooses this domain at 1st level, he or she gains proficiency with martial weapons.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Reaper (Death Domain)</name>			<text>At 1st level, the cleric learns one necromancy cantrip of his or her choice from any spell list. When the cleric casts a necromancy cantrip that normally targets only one creature, the spell can instead target two creatures within range and within 5 feet of each other.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Knowledge Domain</name>			<text>The gods of knowledge &#8212; including Oghma, Boccob, Gilean, Aureon, and Thoth &#8212; value learning and understanding above all. Some teach that knowledge is to be gathered and shared in libraries and universities, or promote the practical knowledge of craft and invention. Some deities hoard knowledge and keep its secrets to themselves. And some promise their followers that they will gain tremendous power if they unlock the secrets of the multiverse. Followers of these gods study esoteric lore, collect old tomes, delve into the secret places of the earth, and learn all they can. Some gods of knowledge promote the practical knowledge of craft and invention, including smith deities like Gond, Reorx, Onatar, Moradin, Hephaestus, and Goibhniu. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Knowledge Domain Spells:</text>			<text>	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>			<text>	1st &#8212; command, identify</text>			<text>	3rd &#8212; augury, suggestion</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; nondetection, speak with dead</text>			<text>	7th &#8212; arcane eye, confusion</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; legend lore, scrying</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Blessings of Knowledge (Knowledge Domain)</name>			<text>At 1st level, you learn two languages of your choice. You also become proficient in your choice of two of the following skills: Arcana, History, Nature, or Religion.</text>			<text>	Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of those skills.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Life Domain</name>			<text>The Life domain focuses on the vibrant positive energy &#8212; one of the fundamental forces of the universe &#8212;  that sustains all life. The gods of life promote vitality and health through healing the sick and wounded, caring for those in need, and driving away the forces of death and undeath. Almost any non-evil deity can claim influence over this domain, particularly agricultural deities (such as Chauntea, Arawai, and Demeter), sun gods (such as Lathander, Pelor, and Re-Horakhty), gods of healing or endurance (such as Ilmater, Mishakal, Apollo, and Diancecht), and gods of home and community (such as Hestia, Hathor, and Boldrei). </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Life Domain Spells:</text>			<text>	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>			<text>	1st &#8212; bless, cure wounds</text>			<text>	3rd &#8212; lesser restoration, spiritual weapon</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; beacon of hope, revivify</text>			<text>	7th &#8212; death ward, guardian of faith</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; mass cure wounds, raise dead</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Bonus Proficiency (Life Domain)</name>			<text>When the cleric chooses this domain at 1st level, he or she gains proficiency with martial weapons.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Disciple of Life (Life Domain)</name>			<text>Also starting at 1st level, your healing spells are more effective. Whenever you use a spell of 1st level or higher to restore hit points to a creature, the creature regains additional hit points equal to 2+the spell's level.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Light Domain</name>			<text>Gods of light &#8212; including Helm, Lathander, Pholtus, Branchala, the Silver Flame, Belenus, Apollo, and Re-Horakhty &#8212; promote the ideals of rebirth and renewal, truth, vigilance, and beauty, often using the symbol of the sun. Some of these gods are portrayed as the sun itself or as a charioteer who guides the sun across the sky. Others are tireless sentinels whose eyes pierce every shadow and see through every deception. Some are deities of beauty and artistry, who teach that art is a vehicle for the soul's improvement. Clerics of a god of light are enlightened souls infused with radiance and the power of their gods' discerning vision, charged with chasing away lies and burning away darkness.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Light Domain Spells:</text>			<text>	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>			<text>	1st &#8212; burning hands, faerie fire</text>			<text>	3rd &#8212; flaming sphere, scorching ray</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; daylight, fireball</text>			<text>	7th &#8212; guardian of faith, wall of fire</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; flame strike, scrying</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Bonus Cantrip (Light Domain)</name>			<text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain the light cantrip if you don't already know it.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Warding Flare (Light Domain)</name>			<text>Also at 1st level, you can interpose divine light between yourself and an attacking enemy. When you are attacked by a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll, causing light to flare before the attacker before it hits or misses. An attacker that can't be blinded is immune to this feature.</text>			<text>	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Nature Domain</name>			<text>Gods of nature are as varied as the natural world itself, from inscrutable gods of the deep forests (such as Silvanus, Obad-Hai, Chislev, Balinor, and Pan) to friendly deities associated with particular springs and groves (such as Eldath). Druids revere nature as a whole and might serve one of these deities, practicing mysterious rites and reciting all-but-forgotten prayers in their own secret tongue. But many of these gods have clerics as well, champions who take a more active role in advancing the interests of a particular nature god. These clerics might hunt the evil monstrosities that despoil the woodlands, bless the harvest of the faithful, or wither the crops of those who anger their gods. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Nature Domain Spells:</text>			<text>	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>			<text>	1st &#8212; animal friendship, speak with animals</text>			<text>	3rd &#8212; barkskin, spike growth</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; plant growth, wind wall</text>			<text>	7th &#8212; dominate beast, grasping vine</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; insect plague, tree stride</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Acolyte of Nature (Nature Domain)</name>			<text>At 1st level, you learn one druid cantrip of your choice. You also gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Nature, or Survival.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Bonus Proficiency (Nature Domain)</name>			<text>When the cleric chooses this domain at 1st level, he or she gains proficiency with martial weapons.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Tempest Domain</name>			<text>Gods whose portfolios include the Tempest domain &#8212; including Talos, Umberlee, Kord, Zeboim, the Devourer, Zeus, and Thor &#8212; govern storms, sea, and sky. They include gods of lightning and thunder, gods of earthquakes, some fire gods, and certain gods of violence, physical strength, and courage. In some pantheons, a god of this domain rules over other deities and is known for swift justice delivered by thunderbolts. In the pantheons of seafaring people, gods of this domain are ocean deities and the patrons of sailors. Tempest gods send their clerics to inspire fear in the common folk, either to keep those folk on the path of righteousness or to encourage them to offer sacrifices of propitiation to ward off divine wrath. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Tempest Domain Spells:</text>			<text>	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>			<text>	1st &#8212; fog cloud, thunderwave</text>			<text>	3rd &#8212; gust of wind, shatter</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; call lightning, sleet storm</text>			<text>	7th &#8212; control water, ice storm</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; destructive wave, insect plague</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Bonus Proficiencies (Tempest Domain)</name>			<text>When you join the College of Lore at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with three skills of your choice.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Wrath of the Storm (Tempest Domain)</name>			<text>Also at 1st level, you can thunderously rebuke attackers. When a creature within 5 feet of you that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to cause the creature to make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 2d8 lightning or thunder damage (your choice) on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one.</text>			<text>	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Trickery Domain</name>			<text>Gods of trickery &#8212; such as Tymora, Beshaba, Olidammara, the Traveler, Garl Glittergold, and Loki &#8212; are mischief-makers and instigators who stand as a constant challenge to the accepted order among both gods and mortals. They're patrons of thieves, scoundrels, gamblers, rebels, and liberators. Their clerics are a disruptive force in the world, puncturing pride, mocking tyrants, stealing from the rich, freeing captives, and flouting hollow traditions. They prefer subterfuge, pranks, deception, and theft rather than direct confrontation.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Trickery Domain Spells:</text>			<text>	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>			<text>	1st &#8212; charm person, disguise self</text>			<text>	3rd &#8212; mirror image, pass without trace</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; blink, dispel magic\7th &#8212; dimension door, polymorph</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; dominate person, modify memory</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Blessing of the Trickster (Trickery Domain)</name>			<text>Starting when you choose this domain at 1st level, you can use your action to touch a willing creature other than yourself to give it advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. This blessing lasts for 1 hour or until you use this feature again.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>War Domain</name>			<text>War has many manifestations. It can make heroes of ordinary people. It can be desperate and horrific, with acts of cruelty and cowardice eclipsing instances of excellence and courage. In either case, the gods of war watch over warriors and reward them for their great deeds. The clerics of such gods excel in battle, inspiring others to fight the good fight or offering acts of violence as prayers. Gods of war include champions of honor and chivalry (such as Torm, Heironeous, and Kiri-Jolith) as well as gods of destruction and pillage (such as Erythnul, the Fury, Gruumsh, and Ares) and gods of conquest and domination (such as Bane, Hextor, and Maglubiyet). Other war gods (such as Tempus, Nike, and Nuada) take a more neutral stance, promoting war in all its manifestations and supporting warriors in any circumstance. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>War Domain Spells:</text>			<text>	At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>			<text>	1st &#8212; divine favor, shield of faith</text>			<text>	3rd &#8212; magic weapon, spiritual weapon</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; crusader's mantle, spirit guardians</text>			<text>	7th &#8212; freedom of movement, stoneskin</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; flame strike, hold monster</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Bonus Proficiencies (War Domain)</name>			<text>When you join the College of Lore at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with three skills of your choice.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>War Priest (War Domain)</name>			<text>From 1st level, your god delivers bolts of inspiration to you while you are engaged in battle. When you use the Attack action, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Craft Domain</name>			<text>The craft domain celebrates all of the endeavors of the intelligent races to build, shape, create, and design, from art to engineering to technology.  In many pantheons, deities of the craft domain taught the crafting arts to their followers directly, in some cases even bringing civilization with them.  Clerics of the craft domain are frequently great artisans, among the very best in their chosen fields.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Craft Domain Spells:</text>			<text>	At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>1st &#8212; create or destroy water, detect magic</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>3rd &#8212; heat metal, magic weapon</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>5th &#8212; create food and water, meld into stone</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>7th &#8212; fabricate, stone shape</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>9th &#8212; creation, legend lore</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Bonus Proficiencies (Craft Domain)</name>			<text>At 1st level, you become proficient with heavy armor, warhammers, and two sets of artisan's tools of your choice.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Master Crafter (Craft Domain)</name>			<text>Also at first level, you gain the ability to weave the divine energies of creation itself into your work. You add your proficiency bonus to any ability check you make to create or repair an item. If you are already proficient in a relevant tool or skill, you add your proficiency from that skill or tool as well, for a total of double your proficiency bonus.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="2">		<slots>3, 3</slots>		<feature>			<name>Channel Divinity</name>			<text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to channel divine energy directly from your deity, using that energy to fuel magical effects. You start with two such effects: Turn Undead and an effect determined by your domain. Some domains grant you additional effects as you advance in levels, as noted in the domain description.</text>			<text>	When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose which effect to create. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your Channel Divinity again.</text>			<text>	Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your cleric spell save DC.</text>			<text>	Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity twice between rests, and beginning at 18th level, you can use it three times between rests. When you finish a short or long rest, you regain your expended uses. </text>		</feature>		<feature>			<name>Channel Divinity: Turn Undead</name>			<text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring the undead. Each undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.</text>			<text>	A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Touch of Death (Death Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 2nd level, the cleric can use Channel Divinity to  destroy another creature's life force by touch.</text>			<text>	When the cleric hits a creature with a melee attack, the cleric can use Channel Divinity to deal extra necrotic damage to the target. The damage equals 5+twice his or her cleric level.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Knowledge of the Ages (Knowledge Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to tap into a divine well of knowledge. As an action, you choose one skill or tool. For 10 minutes, you have proficiency with the chosen skill or tool.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Preserve Life (Life Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to heal the badly injured.</text>			<text>	As an action, you present your holy symbol and evoke healing energy that can restore a number of hit points equal to five times your cleric level. Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you, and divide those hit points among them. This feature can restore a creature to no more than half of its hit point maximum. You can't use this feature on an undead or a construct.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Radiance of the Dawn (Light Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to harness sunlight, banishing darkness and dealing radiant damage to your foes.</text>			<text>	As an action, you present your holy symbol, and any magical darkness within 30 feet of you is dispelled. Additionally, each hostile creature within 30 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes radiant damage equal to 2d10 + your cleric level on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one. A creature that has total cover from you is not affected.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Charm Animals and Plants (Nature Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to charm animals and plants.</text>			<text>	As an action, you present your holy symbol and invoke the name of your deity. Each beast or plant creature that can see you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is charmed by you for 1 minute or until it takes damage. While it is charmed by you, it is friendly to you and other creatures you designate.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Charmed:</text>			<text>&#8226; A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Destructive Wrath (Tempest Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to wield the power of the storm with unchecked ferocity.</text>			<text>	When you roll lightning or thunder damage, you can use your Channel Divinity to deal maximum damage, instead of rolling.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Invoke Duplicity (Trickery Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to create an illusory duplicate of yourself.</text>			<text>	As an action, you create a perfect illusion of yourself that lasts for 1 minute, or until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell). The illusion appears in an unoccupied space that you can see within 30 feet of you. As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the illusion up to 30 feet to a space you can see, but it must remain within 120 feet of you.</text>			<text>	For the duration, you can cast spells as though you were in the illusion's space, but you must use your own senses. Additionally, when both you and your illusion are within 5 feet of a creature that can see the illusion, you have advantage on attack rolls against that creature, given how distracting the illusion is to the target.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Guided Strike (War Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to strike with supernatural accuracy. When you make an attack roll, you can use your Channel Divinity to gain a +10 bonus to the roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Crafter's Insight (Craft Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to tap into the divine powers of creation.   As an action, you can examine an item and determine if it has any magical properties, as if using detect magic, and what those properties are, as if using identify.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">		<slots>3, 4, 2</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="4">		<slots>4, 4, 3</slots>		<feature>			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>			<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>			<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="5">		<slots>3, 4, 3, 2</slots>		<feature>			<name>Destroy Undead</name>			<text>Starting at 5th level, when an undead fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed if its challenge rating is at or below a certain threshold</text>			<text>	At 5th level, you destroy undead of CR 1/2 or lower; at 8th level, CR 1 or lower; at 11th level, CR 2 or lower; at 14th level, CR 3 or lower; and at 17th level, CR 4 or lower.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="6">		<slots>3, 4, 3, 3</slots>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Inescapable Destruction (Death Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 6th level, the cleric's ability to channel negative energy becomes more potent. Necrotic damage dealt by the character's cleric spells and Channel Divinity options ignores resistance to necrotic damage.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Read Thoughts (Knowledge Domain)</name>			<text>At 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to read a creature's thoughts. You can then use your access to the creature's mind to command it.</text>			<text>	As an action, choose one creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature succeeds on the saving throw, you can't use this feature on it again until you finish a long rest.</text>			<text>	If the creature fails its save, you can read its surface thoughts (those foremost in its mind, reflecting its current emotions and what it is actively thinking about) when it is within 60 feet of you. This effect lasts for 1 minute.</text>			<text>	During that time, you can use your action to end this effect and cast the suggestion spell on the creature without expending a spell slot. The target automatically fails its saving throw against the spell.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Blessed Healer (Life Domain)</name>			<text>Beginning at 6th level, the healing spells you cast on others heal you as well. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that restores hit points to a creature other than you, you regain hit points equal to 2+the spell's level.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Improved Flare (Light Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 6th level, you can also use your Warding Flare feature when a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you attacks a creature other than you.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Dampen Elements (Nature Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 6th level, when you or a creature within 30 feet of you takes acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage, you can use your reaction to grant resistance to the creature against that instance of the damage.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Thunderbolt Strike (Tempest Domain)</name>			<text>At 6th level, when you deal lightning damage to a Large or smaller creature, you can also push it up to 10 feet away from you.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Cloak of Shadows (Trickery Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to vanish.</text>			<text>	As an action, you become invisible until the end of your next turn. You become visible if you attack or cast a spell.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Invisible:</text>			<text>&#8226; An invisible creature is impossible to see without the aid of magic or a special sense. For the purpose of hiding, the creature is heavily obscured. The creature's location can be detected by any noise it makes or any tracks it leaves.</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; Attack rolls against the creature have disadvantage, and the creature's attack rolls have advantage.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: War God's Blessing (War Domain)</name>			<text>At 6th level, when a creature within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, you can use your reaction to grant that creature a +10 bonus to the roll, using your Channel Divinity. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Crafter's Talent (Craft Domain)</name>			<text>At 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to create or repair items with astonishing speed, skill, or efficiency. When you make an ability check to create or repair an item, you can expend a use of your Channel Divinity feature to gain one of the following benefits:</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; You have advantage on the ability check to craft or repair the item</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; Crafting or repairing the item takes half as long as usual</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; Crafting or repairing the item uses half as many raw materials as usual.</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>	You can only select one of these bonuses, even if another ability would otherwise allow you to expend more than one use of your Channel Divinity at the same time.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7">		<slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="8">		<slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 2</slots>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Divine Strike (Death Domain)</name>			<text>At 8th level, the cleric gains the ability to infuse his or her weapon strikes with necrotic energy. Once on each of the cleric's turns when he or she hits a creature with a weapon attack, the cleric can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage to the target. When the cleric reaches 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Potent Spellcasting (Knowledge Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Divine Strike (Life Domain)</name>			<text>At 8th level, the cleric gains the ability to infuse his or her weapon strikes with necrotic energy. Once on each of the cleric's turns when he or she hits a creature with a weapon attack, the cleric can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage to the target. When the cleric reaches 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Potent Spellcasting (Light Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Divine Strike (Nature Domain)</name>			<text>At 8th level, the cleric gains the ability to infuse his or her weapon strikes with necrotic energy. Once on each of the cleric's turns when he or she hits a creature with a weapon attack, the cleric can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage to the target. When the cleric reaches 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Divine Strike (Tempest Domain)</name>			<text>At 8th level, the cleric gains the ability to infuse his or her weapon strikes with necrotic energy. Once on each of the cleric's turns when he or she hits a creature with a weapon attack, the cleric can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage to the target. When the cleric reaches 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Divine Strike (Trickery Domain)</name>			<text>At 8th level, the cleric gains the ability to infuse his or her weapon strikes with necrotic energy. Once on each of the cleric's turns when he or she hits a creature with a weapon attack, the cleric can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage to the target. When the cleric reaches 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Divine Strike (War Domain)</name>			<text>At 8th level, the cleric gains the ability to infuse his or her weapon strikes with necrotic energy. Once on each of the cleric's turns when he or she hits a creature with a weapon attack, the cleric can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage to the target. When the cleric reaches 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Divine Strike (Craft Domain)</name>			<text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="9">		<slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 3, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="10">		<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2</slots>		<feature>			<name>Divine Intervention</name>			<text>Beginning at 10th level, you can call on your deity to intervene on your behalf when your need is great.</text>			<text>	Imploring your deity's aid requires you to use your action. Describe the assistance you seek, and roll percentile dice. If you roll a number equal to or lower than your cleric level, your deity intervenes. The DM chooses the nature of the intervention; the effect of any cleric spell or cleric domain spell would be appropriate.</text>			<text>	If your deity intervenes, you can't use this feature again for 7 days. Otherwise, you can use it again after you finish a long rest.</text>			<text>	At 20th level, your call for intervention succeeds automatically, no roll required.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">		<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="12">		<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="13">		<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="14">		<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">		<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="16">		<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="17">		<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1, 1</slots>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Improved Reaper (Death Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 17th level, when the cleric casts a Necromancy spell of 1st through 5th level that targets only one creature, the spell can instead target two creatures within range and within 5 feet of each other. If the spell consumes its material components, the cleric must provide them for each target.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Visions of the Past (Knowledge Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 17th level, you can call up visions of the past that relate to an object you hold or your immediate surroundings. You spend at least 1 minute in meditation and prayer, then receive dreamlike, shadowy glimpses of recent events. You can meditate in this way for a number of minutes equal to your Wisdom score and must maintain concentration during that time, as if you were casting a spell.</text>			<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Object Reading. Holding an object as you meditate, you can see visions of the object's previous owner. After meditating for 1 minute, you learn how the owner acquired and lost the object, as well as the most recent significant event involving the object and that owner. If the object was owned by another creature in the recent past (within a number of days equal to your Wisdom score), you can spend 1 additional minute for each owner to learn the same information about that creature.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Area Reading. As you meditate, you see visions of recent events in your immediate vicinity (a room, street, tunnel, clearing, or the like, up to a 50-foot cube), going back a number of days equal to your Wisdom score. For each minute you meditate, you learn about one significant event, beginning with the most recent. Significant events typically involve powerful emotions, such as battles and betrayals, marriages and murders, births and funerals. However, they might also include more mundane events that are nevertheless important in your current situation.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Supreme Healing (Life Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 17th level, when you would normally roll one or more dice to restore hit points with a spell, you instead use the highest number possible for each die. For example, instead of restoring 2d6 hit points to a creature, you restore 12.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Corona of Light (Light Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 17th level, you can use your action to activate an aura of sunlight that lasts for 1 minute or until you dismiss it using another action. You emit bright light in a 60-foot radius and dim light 30 feet beyond that. Your enemies in the bright light have disadvantage on saving throws against any spell that deals fire or radiant damage.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Master of Nature (Nature Domain)</name>			<text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to command animals and plant creatures. While creatures are charmed by your Charm Animals and Plants feature, you can take a bonus action on your turn to verbally command what each of those creatures will do on its next turn.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Stormborn (Tempest Domain)</name>			<text>At 17th level, you have a flying speed equal to your current walking speed whenever you are not underground or indoors.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Improved Duplicity (Trickery Domain)</name>			<text>At 17th level, you can create up to four duplicates of yourself, instead of one, when you use Invoke Duplicity. As a bonus action on your turn, you can move any number of them up to 30 feet, to a maximum range of 120 feet.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Avatar of Battle (War Domain)</name>			<text>At 17th level, you gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Supreme Crafter (Craft Domain)</name>			<text>Starting at 17th level, when you use your Channel Divinity to gain a bonus to an ability check to craft or repair an item using Crafter's Talent, you select two of the three benefits instead of one. </text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="18">		<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 1, 1, 1, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="19">		<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="20">		<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 2, 1, 1</slots>	</autolevel></class>
	<spell>		<name>Create Food and Water*</name>		<level>3</level>		<school>C</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>30 feet</range>		<components>V, S</components>		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>		<classes>Druid (Desert), Cleric (Craft)</classes>		<text>You create 45 pounds of food and 30 gallons of water on the ground or in containers within range, enough to sustain up to fifteen humanoids or five steeds for 24 hours. The food is bland but nourishing, and spoils if uneaten after 24 hours. The water is clean and doesn't go bad.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 229</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Create or Destroy Water*</name>		<level>1</level>		<school>T</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>30 feet</range>		<components>V, S, M (a drop of water if creating water or a few grains of sand if destroying it)</components>		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>		<classes>Cleric (Craft)</classes>		<text>You either create or destroy water. </text>		<text>	Create Water: You create up to 10 gallons of clean water within range in an open container. Alternatively, the water falls as rain in a 30-foot cube within range, extinguishing exposed flames in the area. </text>		<text>	Destroy Water: You destroy up to 10 gallons of water in an open container within range. Alternatively, you destroy fog in a 30-foot cube within range. </text>		<text>	</text>		<text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you create or destroy 10 additional gallons of water, or the size of the cube increases by 5 feet, for each slot level above 1st.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 229</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Creation*</name>		<level>5</level>		<school>I</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 minute</time>		<range>30 feet</range>		<components>V, S, M (a tiny piece of matter of the same type of the item you plan to create) </components>		<duration>Special</duration>		<classes>Cleric (Craft)</classes>		<text>You pull wisps of shadow material from the Shadowfell to create a nonliving object of vegetable matter within range: soft goods, rope, wood, or something similar. You can also use this spell to create mineral objects such as stone, crystal, or metal. The object created must be no larger than a 5-foot cube, and the object must be of a form and material that you have seen before.</text>		<text>	The duration depends on the object's material. If the object is composed of multiple materials, use the shortest duration. Material &#8212; Duration: Vegetable matter &#8212; 1 day; Stone/crystal &#8212; 12 hours; Precious metals &#8212; 1 hour; Gems &#8212; 10 minutes; Adamantine/Mithral &#8212; 1 minute </text>		<text>	Using any material created by this spell as another spell's material component causes that spell to fail.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the cube increases by 5 feet for each slot level above 5th.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 229</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Detect Magic*</name>		<level>1</level>		<school>D</school>		<ritual>YES</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>Self</range>		<components>V, S</components>		<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>		<classes>Cleric (Craft)</classes>		<text>For the duration, you sense the presence of magic within 30 feet of you. If you sense magic in this way, you can use your action to see a faint aura around any visible creature or object in the area that bears magic, and you learn its school of magic, if any.</text>		<text>	 The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 231</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Fabricate*</name>		<level>4</level>		<school>EV</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>10 minutes</time>		<range>120 feet</range>		<components>V, S</components>		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>		<classes>Cleric (Craft)</classes>		<text>You convert raw materials into products of the same material. For example, you can fabricate a wooden bridge from a clump of trees, a rope from a patch of hemp, and clothes from flax or wool.</text>		<text>	Choose raw materials that you can see within range. You can fabricate a Large or smaller object (contained within a 10-foot cube, or eight connected 5-foot cubes), given a sufficient quantity of raw material. If you are working with metal, stone, or another mineral substance, however, the fabricated object can be no larger than Medium (contained within a single 5-foot cube). The quality of objects made by the spell is commensurate with the quality of the raw materials. </text>		<text>	Creatures or magic items can't be created or transmuted by this spell. You also can't use it to create items that ordinarily require a high degree of craftsmanship, such as jewelry, weapons, glass, or armor, unless you have proficiency with the type of artisan's tools used to craft such objects.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 239</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Heat Metal*</name>		<level>2</level>		<school>T</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>60 feet</range>		<components>V, S, M (a piece of iron and a flame) </components>		<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>		<classes>Cleric (Craft)</classes>		<text>Choose a manufactured metal object, such as a metal weapon or a suit of heavy or medium metal armor, that you can see within range. You cause the object to glow red-hot. Any creature in physical contact with the object takes 2d8 fire damage when you cast the spell. Until the spell ends, you can use a bonus action on each of your subsequent turns to cause this damage again. </text>		<text>	If a creature is holding or wearing the object and takes the damage from it, the creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or drop the object if it can. If it doesn't drop the object, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks until the start of your next turn. </text>		<text>	</text>		<text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot above 2nd.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 250</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>		<roll>2d8</roll>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Legend Lore*</name>		<level>5</level>		<school>D</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>10 minutes</time>		<range>Self</range>		<components>V, S, M (incense worth at least 250 gp, which the spell consumes, and four ivory strips worth at least 50 gp each) </components>		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>		<classes>Cleric (Knowledge), Cleric (Craft)</classes>		<text>Name or describe a person, place, or object. The spell brings to your mind a brief summary of the significant lore about the thing you named. The lore might consist of current tales, forgotten stories, or even secret lore that has never been widely known. If the thing you named isn't of legendary importance, you gain no information. </text>		<text>	The more information you already have about the thing, the more precise and detailed the information you receive is. The information you learn is accurate but might be couched in figurative language. For example, if you have a mysterious magic axe on hand, the spell might yield this information: Woe to the evildoer whose hand touches the axe, for even the haft slices the hand of the evil ones. Only a true Child of Stone, lover and beloved of Moradin, may awaken the true powers of the axe, and only with the sacred word Rudnogg on the lips.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 254</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Magic Weapon*</name>		<level>2</level>		<school>T</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 bonus action</time>		<range>Touch</range>		<components>V, S</components>		<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>		<classes>Cleric (Craft), Cleric (War)</classes>		<text>You touch a nonmagical weapon. Until the spell ends, that weapon becomes a magic weapon with a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls. </text>		<text>	</text>		<text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the bonus increases to +2. When you use a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the bonus increases to +3.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 257</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Meld into Stone*</name>		<level>3</level>		<school>T</school>		<ritual>YES</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>Touch</range>		<components>V, S</components>		<duration>8 hours</duration>		<classes>Druid (Mountain), Cleric (Craft)</classes>		<text>You step into a stone object or surface large enough to fully contain your body, melding yourself and all the equipment you carry with the stone for the duration. Using your movement, you step into the stone at a point you can touch. Nothing of your presence remains visible or otherwise detectable by nonmagical senses. </text>		<text>	While merged with the stone, you can't see what occurs outside it, and any Wisdom (Perception) checks you make to hear sounds outside it are made with disadvantage. You remain aware of the passage of time and can cast spells on yourself while merged in the stone. You can use your movement to leave the stone where you entered it, which ends the spell. You otherwise can't move. </text>		<text>	Minor physical damage to the stone doesn't harm you, but its partial destruction or a change in its shape (to the extent that you no longer fit within it) expels you and deals 6d6 bludgeoning damage to you. The stone's complete destruction (or transmutation into a different substance) expels you and deals 50 bludgeoning damage to you. If expelled, you fall prone in an unoccupied space closest to where you first entered.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 259</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Stone Shape*</name>		<level>4</level>		<school>T</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>Touch</range>		<components>V, S, M (soft clay, which must be worked into roughly the desired shape of the stone object) </components>		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>		<classes>Druid (Mountain), Druid (Underdark), Cleric (Craft)</classes>		<text>You touch a stone object of Medium size or smaller or a section of stone no more than 5 feet in any dimension and form it into any shape that suits your purpose. So, for example, you could shape a large rock into a weapon, idol, or coffer, or make a small passage through a wall, as long as the wall is less than 5 feet thick. You could also shape a stone door or its frame to seal the door shut. The object you create can have up to two hinges and a latch, but finer mechanical detail isn't possible.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 278</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
</compendium>
