<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
<race>	<name>Kalashtar</name>	<size>M</size>	<speed>30</speed>	<ability></ability>	<proficiency></proficiency>	<trait>		<name>Ability Score Increase</name>		<text>Like their human ancestors, Kalashtar vary widely in their natural talents.  Two ability scores of your choice increase by 1.</text>	</trait>	<trait>		<name>Dual Soul</name>		<text>Kalashtar's twinned spirits make social manipulation come naturally. You gain proficiency in Deception, Intimidation, or Persuasion.</text>	</trait>	<trait>		<name>Bastion of Mental Clarity</name>		<text>You have advantage on saving throws against Enchantment spells and effects which would cause you to be charmed.  You don't dream and are immune to the dream spell.</text>	</trait>	<trait>		<name>Mindlink</name>		<text>As an action, you can forge a telepathic bond with another willing creature within 30 feet, which must have an Intelligence of 3 or higher. Once formed, you can communicate with the bonded creature telepathically over any distance on the same plane.  The bond lasts for 1 round per level.  After using this ability, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.  You may only have one bond active at a time.</text>	</trait>	<trait>		<name>Languages</name>		<text>You speak, read, and write Common and Quori.</text>	</trait></race>
<race>	<name>Kalashtar (Psionic)</name>	<size>M</size>	<speed>30</speed>	<ability></ability>	<proficiency></proficiency>	<trait>		<name>Ability Score Increase</name>		<text>Like their human ancestors, Kalashtar vary widely in their natural talents.  Two ability scores of your choice increase by 1.</text>	</trait>	<trait>		<name>Naturally Psionic</name>		<text>You gain 2 psi points.  If you have psi points from another source, such as a class, add these points to your pool; otherwise, you can use these points to power your Mindlink ability.</text>		<text>	You can also spend 1 psi point to reroll a Wisdom, Charisma, or Intelligence save you have just failed.  You may not do so again until you complete a short or long rest.</text>		<text>	If you added these points to an existing psi point pool, you regain them however you regain your other psi points (typically on a long rest).  If these are your only psi points, you regain them on a long rest.</text>	</trait>	<trait>		<name>Bastion of Mental Clarity</name>		<text>You have advantage on saving throws against Enchantment spells and effects which would cause you to be charmed.  You don't dream and are immune to the dream spell.</text>	</trait>	<trait>		<name>Mindlink</name>		<text>As an action, you can spend a psi point to forge a telepathic bond with another willing creature within 30 feet, which must have an Intelligence of 3 or higher. Once formed, you can communicate with the bonded creature telepathically over any distance on the same plane.  The bond lasts for 1 round per level.  After using this ability, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.  You may only have one bond active at a time.</text>	</trait>	<trait>		<name>Languages</name>		<text>You speak, read, and write Common and Quori.</text>	</trait></race>
</compendium>
