<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
<class>	<name>Paladin</name>	<hd>10</hd>	<proficiency>Wisdom, Charisma</proficiency>	<spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>		<autolevel level="1">			<feature>				<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>				<text>Armor: light armor, medium armor, heavy armor, shields</text>				<text>Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons</text>				<text>Tools: none</text>				<text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion</text>			</feature>			<feature>				<name>Starting Equipment</name>				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>				<text> </text>				<text>&#8226; (a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons</text>				<text>&#8226; (a) five javelins or (b) any simple melee weapon</text>				<text>&#8226; (a) a priest's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>				<text>&#8226; Chain mail and a holy symbol </text>				<text> </text>				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 x 10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>			</feature>		</autolevel>	<autolevel level="1">		<slots></slots>		<feature>			<name>Divine Sense</name>			<text>The presence of strong evil registers on your senses like a noxious odor, and powerful good rings like heavenly music in your ears. As an action, you can open your awareness to detect such forces. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any celestial, fiend, or undead within 60 feet of you that is not behind total cover. You know the type (celestial, fiend, or undead) of any being whose presence you sense, but not its identity (the vampire Count Strahd von Zarovich, for instance). Within the same radius, you also detect the presence of any place or object that has been consecrated or desecrated, as with the hallow spell.</text>			<text>	You can use this feature a number of times equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier. When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended uses.</text>		</feature>		<feature>			<name>Lay on Hands</name>			<text>Your blessed touch can heal wounds. You have a pool of healing power that replenishes when you take a long rest. With that pool, you can restore a total number of hit points equal to your paladin level x 5.</text>			<text>	As an action, you can touch a creature and draw power from the pool to restore a number of hit points to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool.</text>			<text>	Alternatively, you can expend 5 hit points from your pool of healing to cure the target of one disease or neutralize one poison affecting it. You can cure multiple diseases and neutralize multiple poisons with a single use of Lay on Hands, expending hit points separately for each one.</text>			<text>	This feature has no effect on undead and constructs.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="2">		<slots>, 2</slots>		<feature>			<name>Spellcasting</name>			<text>By 2nd level, you have learned to draw on divine magic through meditation and prayer to cast spells as a cleric does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the paladin spell list. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Preparing and Casting Spells:</text>			<text>	The Paladin table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells. To cast one of your paladin spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>			<text>	You prepare the list of paladin spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the paladin spell list. When you do so, choose a number of paladin spells equal to your Charisma modifier+half your paladin level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>			<text>	For example, if you are a 5th-level paladin, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Charisma of 14, your list of prepared spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells.</text>			<text>	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of paladin spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>			<text>	Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your paladin spells, since their power derives from the strength of your convictions. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a paladin spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>			<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>			<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Spellcasting Focus:</text>			<text>	You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your paladin spells.</text>		</feature>		<feature>			<name>Divine Smite</name>			<text>Starting at 2nd level, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend one spell slot to deal radiant damage to the target, in addition to the weapon's damage. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level spell slot, plus 1d8 for each spell level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8. The damage increases by 1d8 if the target is an undead or a fiend.</text>		</feature>		<feature>			<name>Fighting Style</name>			<text>At 2nd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options: Defense, Dueling, Great Weapon Fighting, Mariner, or Protection. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Fighting Style: Defense</name>			<text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name>			<text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</name>			<text>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Fighting Style: Mariner</name>			<text>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Fighting Style: Protection</name>			<text>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">		<slots>, 3</slots>		<feature>			<name>Divine Health</name>			<text>By 3rd level, the divine magic flowing through you makes you immune to disease.</text>		</feature>		<feature>			<name>Sacred Oath</name>			<text>When you reach 3rd level, you swear the oath that binds you as a paladin forever. Up to this time you have been in a preparatory stage, committed to the path but not yet sworn to it. Now you choose the Oath of Devotion, the Oath of the Ancients, or the Oath of Vengeance, all detailed at the end of the class description.</text>			<text>	Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 15th, and 20th level. Those features include oath spells and the Channel Divinity feature. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Oath Spells:</text>			<text>	Each oath has a list of associated spells. You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the oath description. Once you gain access to an oath spell, you always have it prepared. Oath spells don't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</text>			<text>	If you gain an oath spell that doesn't appear on the paladin spell list, the spell is nonetheless a paladin spell for you.</text>		</feature>		<feature>			<name>Channel Divinity</name>			<text>Your oath allows you to channel divine energy to fuel magical effects. Each Channel Divinity option provided by your oath explains how to use it.</text>			<text>	When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose which option to use. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your Channel Divinity again.</text>			<text>	Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your paladin spell save DC.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Oath of Devotion</name>			<text>The Oath of Devotion binds a paladin to the loftiest ideals of justice, virtue, and order. Sometimes called cavaliers, white knights, or holy warriors, these paladins meet the ideal of the knight in shining armor, acting with honor in pursuit of justice and the greater good. They hold themselves to the highest standards of conduct, and some, for better or worse, hold the rest of the world to the same standards. Many who swear this oath are devoted to gods of law and good and use their gods' tenets as the measure of their devotion. They hold angels &#8212; the perfect servants of good &#8212; as their ideals, and incorporate images of angelic wings into their helmets or coats of arms. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Tenets of Devotion:</text>			<text>	Though the exact words and strictures of the Oath of Devotion vary, paladins of this oath share these tenets.</text>			<text>	Honesty. Don't lie or cheat. Let your word be your promise.</text>			<text>	Courage. Never fear to act, though caution is wise.</text>			<text>	Compassion. Aid others, protect the weak, and punish those who threaten them. Show mercy to your foes, but temper it with wisdom.</text>			<text>	Honor. Treat others with fairness, and let your honorable deeds be an example to them. Do as much good as possible while causing the least amount of harm.</text>			<text>	Duty. Be responsible for your actions and their consequences, protect those entrusted to your care, and obey those who have just authority over you. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Oath Spells:</text>			<text>	You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.</text>			<text>	3rd &#8212; protection from evil and good, sanctuary</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; lesser restoration, zone of truth</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; beacon of hope, dispel magic</text>			<text>	13th &#8212; freedom of movement, guardian of faith</text>			<text>	17th &#8212; commune, flame strike</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Sacred Weapon (Oath of Devotion)</name>			<text>As an action, you can imbue one weapon that you are holding with positive energy, using your Channel Divinity. For 1 minute, you add your Charisma modifier to attack rolls made with that weapon (with a minimum bonus of +1). The weapon also emits bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light 20 feet beyond that. If the weapon is not already magical, it becomes magical for the duration.</text>			<text>	You can end this effect on your turn as part of any other action. If you are no longer holding or carrying this weapon, or if you fall unconscious, this effect ends.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Turn the Unholy (Oath of Devotion)</name>			<text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring fiends and undead, using your Channel Divinity. Each fiend or undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes damage.</text>			<text>	A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Oath of the Ancients</name>			<text>The Oath of the Ancients is as old as the race of elves and the rituals of the druids. Sometimes called fey knights, green knights, or horned knights, paladins who swear this oath cast their lot with the side of the light in the cosmic struggle against darkness because they love the beautiful and life-giving things of the world, not necessarily because they believe in principles of honor, courage, and justice. They adorn their armor and clothing with images of growing things &#8212; leaves, antlers, or flowers &#8212; to reflect their commitment to preserving life and light in the world. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Tenets of the Ancients:</text>			<text>	The tenets of the Oath of the Ancients have been preserved for uncounted centuries. This oath emphasizes the principles of good above any concerns of law or chaos. Its four central principles are simple. </text>			<text>	Kindle the Light.</text>			<text>	Through your acts of mercy, kindness, and forgiveness, kindle the light of hope in the world, beating back despair. </text>			<text>	Shelter the Light.</text>			<text>	Where there is good, beauty, love, and laughter in the world, stand against the wickedness that would swallow it. Where life flourishes, stand against the forces that would render it barren. </text>			<text>	Preserve Your Own Light.</text>			<text>	Delight in song and laughter, in beauty and art. If you allow the light to die in your own heart, you can't preserve it in the world. </text>			<text>	Be the Light.</text>			<text>	Be a glorious beacon for all who live in despair. Let the light of your joy and courage shine forth in all your deeds. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Oath Spells:</text>			<text>	You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>3rd &#8212; ensnaring strike, speak with animals</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; moonbeam, misty step</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; plant growth, protection from energy</text>			<text>	13th &#8212; ice storm, stoneskin</text>			<text>	17th &#8212; commune with nature, tree stride</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Nature's Wrath (Oath of the Ancients)</name>			<text>You can use your Channel Divinity to invoke primeval forces to ensnare a foe. As an action, you can cause spectral vines to spring up and reach for a creature within 10 feet of you that you can see. The creature must succeed on a Strength or Dexterity saving throw (its choice) or be restrained. While restrained by the vines, the creature repeats the saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a success, it frees itself and the vines vanish.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Restrained:</text>			<text>&#8226; A restrained creature's speed becomes 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; The creature has disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Turn the Faithless (Oath of the Ancients)</name>			<text>You can use your Channel Divinity to utter ancient words that are painful for fey and fiends to hear. As an action, you present your holy symbol, and each fey or fiend within 30 feet of you that can hear you must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is turned for 1 minute or until it takes damage.</text>			<text>	A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</text>			<text>	If the creature's true form is concealed by an illusion, shapeshifting, or other effect, that form is revealed while it is turned.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Oath of Vengeance</name>			<text>The Oath of Vengeance is a solemn commitment to punish those who have committed a grievous sin. When evil forces slaughter helpless villagers, when an entire people turns against the will of the gods, when a thieves' guild grows too violent and powerful, when a dragon rampages through the countryside &#8212; at times like these, paladins arise and swear an Oath of Vengeance to set right that which has gone wrong. To these paladins &#8212;  sometimes called avengers or dark knights &#8212; their own purity is not as important as delivering justice.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Tenets of Vengeance:</text>			<text>	The tenets of the Oath of Vengeance vary by paladin, but all the tenets revolve around punishing wrongdoers by any means necessary. Paladins who uphold these tenets are willing to sacrifice even their own righteousness to mete out justice upon those who do evil, so the paladins are often neutral or lawful neutral in alignment. The core principles of the tenets are brutally simple. </text>			<text>	Fight the Greater Evil.</text>			<text>	Faced with a choice of fighting my sworn foes or combating a lesser evil. I choose the greater evil. </text>			<text>	No Mercy for the Wicked.</text>			<text>	Ordinary foes might win my mercy, but my sworn enemies do not. </text>			<text>	By Any Means Necessary.</text>			<text>	My qualms can't get in the way of exterminating my foes. </text>			<text>	Restitution.</text>			<text>	If my foes wreak ruin on the world, it is because I failed to stop them. I must help those harmed by their misdeeds. </text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Oath Spells:</text>			<text>	You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>3rd &#8212; bane, hunter's mark</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; hold person, misty step</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; haste, protection from energy</text>			<text>	13th &#8212; banishment, dimension door</text>			<text>	17th &#8212; hold monster, scrying</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Abjure Enemy (Oath of Vengeance)</name>			<text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer of denunciation, using your Channel Divinity. Choose one creature within 60 feet of you that you can see. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw, unless it is immune to being frightened. Fiends and undead have disadvantage on this saving throw.</text>			<text>	On a failed save, the creature is frightened for 1 minute or until it takes any damage. While frightened, the creature's speed is 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.</text>			<text>	On a successful save, the creature's speed is halved for 1 minute or until the creature takes any damage.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Vow of Enmity (Oath of Vengeance)</name>			<text>As a bonus action, you can utter a vow of enmity against a creature you can see within 10 feet of you, using your Channel Divinity. You gain advantage on attack rolls against the creature for 1 minute or until it drops to 0 hit points or falls unconscious.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Frightened:</text>			<text>&#8226; A frightened creature has disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls while the source of its fear is within line of sight.</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; The creature can't willingly move closer to the source of its fear.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Oathbreaker</name>			<text>An Oathbreaker is a paladin who breaks his or her sacred oaths to pursue some dark ambition or serve an evil power. Whatever light burned in the paladin's heart has been extinguished. Only darkness remains.</text>			<text>	A paladin must be evil and at least 3rd level to become an Oathbreaker. The paladin replaces the features specific to his or her Sacred Oath with Oathbreaker features.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Oathbreaker Spells:</text>			<text>	An Oathbreaker paladin loses previously gained oath spells and instead gains the following Oathbreaker spells at the paladin levels listed.</text>			<text>	3rd &#8212; hellish rebuke, inflict wounds</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; crown of madness, darkness</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; animate dead, bestow curse</text>			<text>	13th &#8212; blight, confusion</text>			<text>	17th &#8212; contagion, dominate person</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Control Undead (Oathbreaker)</name>			<text>As an action, the paladin targets one undead creature he or she can see within 30 feet of him or her. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target must obey the paladin's commands for the next 24 hours, or until the paladin uses this Channel Divinity option again. An undead whose challenge rating is equal to or greater than the paladin's level is immune to this effect.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Dreadful Aspect (Oathbreaker)</name>			<text>As an action, the paladin channels the darkest emotions and focuses them into a burst of magical menace. Each creature of the paladin's choice within 30 feet of the paladin must make a Wisdom saving throw if it can see the paladin. On a failed save, the target is frightened of the paladin for 1 minute. If a creature frightened by this effect ends its turn more than 30 feet away from the paladin, it can attempt another Wisdom saving throw to end the effect on it.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Frightened:</text>			<text>&#8226; A frightened creature has disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls while the source of its fear is within line of sight.</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; The creature can't willingly move closer to the source of its fear.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Oath of Silence</name>			<text>Paladins that swear the Oath of Silence oppose the wrongful use of arcane magic and sorcery. They consider the abuse of such power to be an aff ront to the gods that gave the gift of magic to mortals. Some may even go so far as to believe that such power was never intended to wielded at all by mere mortals and oppose its use completely All that swear this oath agree on one thing: they will not rest until they have silenced those that use magic for purposes beyond what the divine powers intended. </text>			<text>	</text>			<text>Tenants of Silence: </text>			<text>	The tenants of this oath revolve around the divine origins of magic and the strict regulation of how magic should (or shouldn&#8217;t) be used by mortal beings. </text>			<text>	All magic is divine. The weave of magic was created by higher powers for the benefit of all beings. All magical power flows down from on high. </text>			<text>	Magic is a gift. Mortals that can harness the power of magic, even arcane magic, are able to do so only because higher powers have bestowed a mighty gift upon them. </text>			<text>	Magic is not to be misused. The gift of magic was not meant to be used to enrich, oppress, or enslave, but to benefit all mortals. It shall not be wielded improperly. </text>			<text>	Misuse of magic must be opposed. I will silence those who profane the sacred language of magic by abusing its power.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>Oath Spells:</text>			<text>	You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.</text>			<text>	3rd &#8212; detect magic, shield</text>			<text>	5th &#8212; see invisibility, silence</text>			<text>	9th &#8212; counterspell, dispel magic</text>			<text>	13th &#8212; freedom of movement, locate creature</text>			<text>	17th &#8212; circle of power, hallow</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Mute Opposition (Oath of Silence)</name>			<text>As a bonus action, you allow divine power to wordlessly flow through you. For the next minute, you can ignore the verbal components of any of your paladin spells that you cast as long as you are brandishing your holy symbol as a spellcasting focus.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Channel Divinity: Righteous Interruption (Oath of Silence)</name>			<text>You can expend your Channel Divinity as a bonus action whenever you damage a creature that is concentrating on a spell. If you do, the DC of that creature&#8217;s Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration equals 13 or the amount of damage that you dealt, whichever number is higher, instead of the normal DC.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="4">		<slots>, 3</slots>		<feature>			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>			<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>			<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="5">		<slots>, 4, 2</slots>		<feature>			<name>Extra Attack</name>			<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="6">		<slots>, 4, 2</slots>		<feature>			<name>Aura of Protection</name>			<text>Starting at 6th level, whenever you or a friendly creature within 10 feet of you must make a saving throw, the creature gains a bonus to the saving throw equal to your Charisma modifier (with a minimum bonus of +1). You must be conscious to grant this bonus.</text>			<text>	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7">		<slots>, 4, 3</slots>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Aura of Devotion (Oath of Devotion)</name>			<text>Starting at 7th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can't be charmed while you are conscious.</text>			<text>	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Aura of Warding (Oath of the Ancients)</name>			<text>Beginning at 7th level, ancient magic lies so heavily upon you that it forms an eldritch ward. You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you have resistance to damage from spells.</text>			<text>	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Relentless Avenger (Oath of Vengeance)</name>			<text>By 7th level, your supernatural focus helps you close off a foe's retreat. When you hit a creature with an opportunity attack, you can move up to half your speed immediately after the attack and as part of the same reaction. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Aura of Hate (Oathbreaker)</name>			<text>Starting at 7th level, the paladin, as well as any fiends and undead within 10 feet of the paladin, gains a bonus to melee weapon damage rolls equal to the paladin's Charisma modifier (minimum of +1). A creature can benefit from this feature from only one paladin at a time.</text>			<text>	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Cursebreaker (Oath of Silence)</name>			<text>Starting at 7th level, when you use your Lay on Hands feature, you can expend 10 hit points from your pool of healing to cause one curse aff ecting the touched creature to end. You can remove multiple curses with a single use of Lay on Hands by expending hit points separately for each one.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="8">		<slots>, 4, 3</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="9">		<slots>, 4, 3, 2</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="10">		<slots>, 4, 3, 2</slots>		<feature>			<name>Aura of Courage</name>			<text>Starting at 10th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can't be frightened while you are conscious.</text>			<text>	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">		<slots>, 4, 3, 3</slots>		<feature>			<name>Improved Divine Smite</name>			<text>By 11th level, you are so suffused with righteous might that all your melee weapon strikes carry divine power with them. Whenever you hit a creature with a melee weapon, the creature takes an extra 1d8 radiant damage. If you also use your Divine Smite with an attack, you add this damage to the extra damage of your Divine Smite.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="12">		<slots>, 4, 3, 3</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="13">		<slots>, 4, 3, 3, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="14">		<slots>, 4, 3, 3, 1</slots>		<feature>			<name>Cleansing Touch</name>			<text>Beginning at 14th level, you can use your action to end one spell on yourself or on one willing creature that you touch.</text>			<text>	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">		<slots>, 4, 3, 3, 2</slots>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Purity of Spirit (Oath of Devotion)</name>			<text>Beginning at 15th level, you are always under the effects of a protection from evil and good spell.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Undying Sentinel (Oath of the Ancients)</name>			<text>Starting at 15th level, when you are reduced to 0 hit points and are not killed outright, you can choose to drop to 1 hit point instead. Once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>			<text>	Additionally, you suffer none of the drawbacks of old age, and you can't be aged magically.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Soul of Vengeance (Oath of Vengeance)</name>			<text>Starting at 15th level, the authority with which you speak your Vow of Enmity gives you greater power over your foe. When a creature under the effect of your Vow of Enmity makes an attack, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature if it is within range.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Supernatural Resistance (Oathbreaker)</name>			<text>At 15th level, the paladin gains resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Stunning Smite (Oath of Silence)</name>			<text>Starting at 15th level when you use your Divine Smite against a creature, in addition to dealing extra radiant damage, you may also unleash a burst of divine energy which has a chance to stupefy your target. If you do, the target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the beginning of your next turn. The DC of this saving throw is equal to the saving throw DC for your paladin spells. Once you use this ability, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a short or a long rest.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="16">		<slots>, 4, 3, 3, 2</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="17">		<slots>, 4, 3, 3, 3, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="18">		<slots>, 4, 3, 3, 3, 1</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="19">		<slots>, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2</slots>	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="20">		<slots>, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2</slots>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Holy Nimbus (Oath of Devotion)</name>			<text>At 20th level, as an action, you can emanate an aura of sunlight. For 1 minute, bright light shines from you in a 30-foot radius, and dim light shines 30 feet beyond that.</text>			<text>	Whenever an enemy creature starts its turn in the bright light, the creature takes 10 radiant damage.</text>			<text>	In addition, for the duration, you have advantage on saving throws against spells cast by fiends or undead.</text>			<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Elder Champion (Oath of the Ancients)</name>			<text>At 20th level, you can assume the form of an ancient force of nature, taking on an appearance you choose. For example, your skin might turn green or take on a bark-like texture, your hair might become leafy or mosslike, or you might sprout antlers or a lion-like mane.</text>			<text>	Using your action, you undergo a transformation. For 1 minute, you gain the following benefits.</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; At the start of each of your turns, you regain 10 hit points.</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; Whenever you cast a paladin spell that has a casting time of 1 action, you can cast it using a bonus action instead.</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; Enemy creatures within 10 feet of you have disadvantage on saving throws against your paladin spells and Channel Divinity options.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Avenging Angel (Oath of Vengeance)</name>			<text>At 20th level, you can assume the form of an angelic avenger. Using your action, you undergo a transformation. For 1 hour, you gain the following benefits.</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; Wings sprout from your back and grant you a flying speed of 60 feet.</text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; You emanate an aura of menace in a 30-foot radius. The first time any enemy creature enters the aura or starts its turn there during a battle, the creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you for 1 minute or until it takes any damage. Attack rolls against the frightened creature have advantage.</text>			<text>	 </text>			<text>	 Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Dread Lord (Oathbreaker)</name>			<text>At 20th-level, the paladin can, as an action, surround himself or herself with an aura of gloom that lasts for 1 minute. The aura reduces any bright light in a 30-foot radius around the paladin to dim light. Whenever an enemy that is frightened by the paladin starts its turn in the aura, it takes 4d10 psychic damage. Additionally, the paladin and creatures he or she chooses in the aura are draped in deeper shadow. Creatures that rely on sight have disadvantage on attack rolls against creatures draped in this shadow.</text>			<text>	While the aura lasts, the paladin can use a bonus action on his or her turn to cause the shadows in the aura to attack one creature. The paladin makes a melee spell attack against the target. If the attack hits, the target takes necrotic damage equal to 3d10 +the paladin's Charisma modifier.</text>			<text>	After activating the aura, the paladin can't do so again until he or she finishes a long rest.</text>		</feature>		<feature optional="YES">			<name>Paragon of Silence</name>			<text>At 20th level, you can use an action to unleash your inner divinity, causing a transfiguration of your form. A shimmering aura of divine energy surrounds you and for 1 minute, you gain the following benefits: </text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; You have resistance to damage from spells. </text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; Enemy creatures within 10 feet of you can&#8217;t move or travel using teleportation or by extradimensional or interplanar means. </text>			<text>	</text>			<text>&#8226; When you score a critical hit with a weapon attack, the target of the attack must make an Intelligence saving throw. The DC of this saving throw is equal to the saving throw DC for your paladin spells. On a failed save, the creature&#8217;s Intelligence and Charisma scores become 1. The creature can&#8217;t cast spells, activate magic items, understand language, or communicate in any intelligible way. At the end of every 24 hours, the creature can repeat its saving throw against this effect. If it succeeds on its saving throw, the effect ends. The effect can also be ended by Greater Restoration, Heal, or a Wish. </text>			<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you fi nish a long rest.</text>		</feature>	</autolevel></class>
	<spell>		<name>Circle of Power*</name>		<level>5</level>		<school>A</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>Self (30-foot radius)</range>		<components>V</components>		<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>		<classes>Paladin (Silence)</classes>		<text>Divine energy radiates out from you, distorting and diffusing magical energy within 30 feet of you. Until the spell ends, the sphere moves with you, centered on you. For the duration, each friendly creature in the area (including you) has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects. Additionally, when an affected creature succeeds on a saving throw made against a spell or magical effect that allows it to make a saving throw to take only half damage, it instead takes no damage if it succeeds on the saving throw.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 222</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Counterspell*</name>		<level>3</level>		<school>A</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 reaction</time>		<range>60 feet</range>		<components>S</components>		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>		<classes>Paladin (Silence)</classes>		<text>You attempt to interrupt a creature in the process of casting a spell. If the creature is casting a spell of or lower, its spell fails and has no effect. If it is casting a spell of or higher, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell's level. On a success, the creature's spell fails and has no effect. </text>		<text>	</text>		<text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the interrupted spell has no effect if its level is less than or equal to the level of the spell slot you used.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 228</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Detect Magic*</name>		<level>1</level>		<school>D</school>		<ritual>YES</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>Self</range>		<components>V, S</components>		<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>		<classes>Paladin (Silence)</classes>		<text>For the duration, you sense the presence of magic within 30 feet of you. If you sense magic in this way, you can use your action to see a faint aura around any visible creature or object in the area that bears magic, and you learn its school of magic, if any.</text>		<text>	 The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 231</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Dispel Magic*</name>		<level>3</level>		<school>A</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>120 feet</range>		<components>V, S</components>		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>		<classes>Cleric (Trickery), Paladin (Devotion), Paladin (Silence)</classes>		<text>Choose any creature, object, or magical effect within range. Any spell of 3rd level or lower on the target ends. For each spell of or higher on the target, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10+the spell's level. On a successful check, the spell ends. </text>		<text>	</text>		<text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you automatically end the effects of a spell on the target if the spell's level is equal to or less than the level of the spell slot you used.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 234</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Freedom of Movement*</name>		<level>4</level>		<school>A</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>Touch</range>		<components>V, S, M (a leather strap, bound around the arm or a similar appendage)</components>		<duration>1 hour</duration>		<classes>Cleric (War), Druid (Arctic), Druid (Coast), Druid (Forest), Druid (Grassland), Druid (Swamp), Paladin (Devotion), Paladin (Silence)</classes>		<text>You touch a willing creature. For the duration, the target's movement is unaffected by difficult terrain, and spells and other magical effects can neither reduce the target's speed nor cause the target to be paralyzed or restrained. </text>		<text>	The target can also spend 5 feet of movement to automatically escape from nonmagical restraints, such as manacles or a creature that has it grappled. Finally, being underwater imposes no penalties on the target's movement or attacks.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 244</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Hallow*</name>		<level>5</level>		<school>EV</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>24 hours</time>		<range>Touch</range>		<components>V, S, M (herbs, oils, and incense worth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes)</components>		<duration>Until dispelled</duration>		<classes>Paladin (Silence)</classes>		<text>You touch a point and infuse an area around it with holy (or unholy) power. The area can have a radius up to 60 feet, and the spell fails if the radius includes an area already under the effect a hallow spell. The affected area is subject to the following effects. </text>		<text>	First, celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead can't enter the area, nor can such creatures charm, frighten, or possess creatures within it. Any creature charmed, frightened, or possessed by such a creature is no longer charmed, frightened, or possessed upon entering the area. You can exclude one or more of those types of creatures from this effect. </text>		<text>	Second, you can bind an extra effect to the area. Choose the effect from the following list, or choose an effect offered by the DM. Some of these effects apply to creatures in the area, you can designate whether the effect applies to all creatures, creatures that follow a specific deity or leader, or creatures of a specific sort, such as ores or trolls. When a creature that would be affected enters the spell's area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it can make a Charisma saving throw. On a success, the creature ignores the extra effect until it leaves the area. </text>		<text>	Courage: Affected creatures can't be frightened while in the area. </text>		<text>	Darkness: Darkness fills the area. Normal light, as well as magical light created by spells of a lower level than the slot you used to cast this spell, can't illuminate the area. </text>		<text>	Daylight: Bright light fills the area. Magical darkness created by spells of a lower level than the slot you used to cast this spell can't extinguish the light. </text>		<text>	Energy Protection:. Affected creatures in the area have resistance to one damage type of your choice, except for bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing. </text>		<text>	Energy Vulnerability: Affected creatures in the area have vulnerability to one damage type of your choice, except for bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing. </text>		<text>	Everlasting Rest: Dead bodies interred in the area can't be turned into undead. </text>		<text>	Extradimensional Interference: Affected creatures can't move or travel using teleportation or by extradimensional or interplanar means. </text>		<text>	Fear: Affected creatures are frightened while in the area. </text>		<text>	Silence: No sound can emanate from within the area, and no sound can reach into it.</text>		<text>	Tongues: Affected creatures can communicate with any other creature in the area, even if they don't share a common language. </text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 249</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Locate Creature*</name>		<level>4</level>		<school>D</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>Self</range>		<components>V, S, M (a bit of fur from a bloodhound) </components>		<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>		<classes>Druid (Swamp), Paladin (Silence)</classes>		<text>Describe or name a creature that is familiar to you. You sense the direction to the creature's location, as long as that creature is within 1,000 feet of you. If the creature is moving, you know the direction of its movement. </text>		<text>	The spell can locate a specific creature known to you, or the nearest creature of a specific kind (such as a human or a unicorn), so long as you have seen such a creature up close &#8212; within 30 feet &#8212; at least once. If the creature you described or named is in a different form, such as being under the effects of a polymorph spell, this spell doesn't locate the creature. </text>		<text>	This spell can't locate a creature if running water at least 10 feet wide blocks a direct path between you and the creature.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 256</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>See Invisibility*</name>		<level>2</level>		<school>D</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>Self</range>		<components>V, S, M (A pinch of Talc and a small sprinkling of powdered silver) </components>		<duration>1 hour</duration>		<classes>Paladin (Silence)</classes>		<text>For the duration, you see invisible creatures and objects as if they were visible, and you can see into the Ethereal Plane. Ethereal creatures and objects appear ghostly and translucent.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 274</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Shield*</name>		<level>1</level>		<school>A</school>		<ritual>NO</ritual>		<time>1 reaction</time>		<range>Self</range>		<components>V, S</components>		<duration>1 round</duration>		<classes>Paladin (Silence)</classes>		<text>An invisible barrier of magical force appears and protects you. Until the start of your next turn, you have a +5 bonus to AC, including against the triggering attack, and you take no damage from magic missile.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 275</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
	<spell>		<name>Silence*</name>		<level>2</level>		<school>I</school>		<ritual>YES</ritual>		<time>1 action</time>		<range>120 feet</range>		<components>V, S</components>		<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>		<classes>Druid (Desert), Paladin (Silence)</classes>		<text>For the duration, no sound can be created within or pass through a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on a point you choose within range. Any creature or object entirely inside the sphere is immune to thunder damage, and creatures are deafened while entirely inside it. Casting a spell that includes a verbal component is impossible there.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 275</text>		<text />		<text>* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text>	</spell>
</compendium>
